Guide to the William Henry Hill papers, 1878-1964
Hill, William Henry papers, 1878-1964
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
William Henry Hill papers, 1878-1964, 1918-1964 (bulk)
2398
William Henry Hill, 1877-1972.
5 cubic ft.
Correspondence, citations, awards, photographs, legal documents, political cartoons, payroll records, pamphlets, books, maps, and other material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers of William Henry Hill, who was a New York State and United States congressman, National Convention delegate, member of the New York State Republican Party executive committee, chairman of the Broome County Republicans, publisher of the Binghamton Sun, and Central New York State Parks Commissioner.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
William Henry Hill was a New York State and United States congressman, National Convention delegate, member of the New York State Republican Party executive committee, chairman of the Broome County Republicans, publisher of the Binghamton Sun, and Central New York State Parks Commissioner.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Mostly correspondence between Hill and W. Sterling Cole, Thomas E. Dewey, W. Averell Harriman, Herbert Hoover, Irving M. Ives, Jacob K. Javits, Kenneth B. Keating, Richard M. Nixon, Howard Robison, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Republican National Committee Chairman Hubert Work, New York Republican State Committee Chairmen William L. Pfeiffer, Dean P. Taylor, and L. Judson Morhouse, and others, relating to Hill's management of the 1928 Hoover preconvention campaign and to the presidential elections of 1928, 1932, 1952, and 1956; thanking Hill for political support given personally or through his newspaper; expressing opinions on local or national poitical issues; concerning meetings of or issues facing the Central New York State Parks Commission; and pertaining to Hill's inclusion in the Binghamton Chapter of the American Legion's Hall of Fame (1951); and other topics. Also, Hill's citations and awards, correspondence and other items pertaining to the SUN'S advertising and policy; original political cartoons by Bob Satterfield and others; a deposition, complaint, and other items (1932-33) pertaining to the indictment of the directors of the closed State Bank of Binghamton; payroll records (2 volumes, 1915-1924 and 1919-1924) of the BINGHAMTON REPUBLICAN and general accounts; photographs, including autographed pictures of Herbert Hoover; related miscellaneous pamphlets, books, and printed material; maps and plans of Johnson City and Endicott, New York.
Also, a large engraving of Abraham Lincoln and portrait of William McKinley, probably hung in Hill's office at one point.
See Accession Folder for a detailed list of correspondence and photographs.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Hill, William Henry, 1877-1972.; Cole, W. Sterling.; Dewey, Thomas E. (Thomas Edmund), 1902-1971.; Harriman, W. Averell (William Averell), 1891-; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; Ives, Irving McNeil, 1896-1962.; Javits, Jacob K. (Jacob Koppel), 1904-; Keating, Kenneth B.; Morhouse, L. Judson.; Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-; Pfeiffer, William L.; Robison, Howard.; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich), 1908-1979.; Satterfield, Bob.; Taylor, Dean P.; Work, Hubert.; American Legion.; Central New York State Parks Commission.; State Bank of Binghamton.
Subjects:
Banks and banking.; Electioneering.; Newspaper publishing.; Parks--New York.; Political cartoons.; Politics, Practical.; Politicians.; Publishers.
Places:
Endicott (N.Y.)--Maps.; Johnson City (N.Y.)--Maps.; United States--Politics and government.; United States--Politics and government--Caricatures and cartoons.
Form and Genre Terms:
Political cartoons.; Maps.; Payrolls.; Photographs.; Plans (drawings).
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence, 1918 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1927-June 1951 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, July 1951-Dec. 1952 (Box 2)
- Correspondence, Jan.-Dec. 1953 (Box 3)
- Correspondence, Jan.-Dec. 1954 (Box 4)
- Correspondence, Jan.-Dec. 1955 (Box 5)
- Correspondence, Jan. 1956-Dec. 1957 (Box 6)
- Correspondence, Jan. 1958-Mar. 1959 (Box 7)
- Correspondence, [Apr. 1959-Aug.1961]-1964 (Box 8)
- Miscellaneous items:
  - Misc. lists, mimeo items, Hill for Senator item (ca. 1916), a menu, etc. (Box 9)
  - Binghamton Sun items (Box 9)
  - Receipt from Republic Printing Co., Apr. 27, 1878 (Box 9)
  - Delegate ticket to Repub. State Convention, 1883 (Box 9)
  - Delegate plates to Repub. Nat'l Convention, 1932, 1940 (Box 9)
  - Misc. notes and memos (Box 9)
  - Newsclipping and metal plate of Rockefeller's first letter as Governor (written to Hill), Jan. 5, 1959 (Box 9)
  - Misc. cards (e.g. credit cards, membership cards) (Box 9)
  - Certificates, 1913-1959 (Box 9)
  - Invitations, admission cards, 1929-1957, n.d. (Box 9)
- Books and pamphlets (see listing in Accession Folder) (Box 10-11)
- Wooden plaque (presented to Hill by Hall of Fame Congress, American Legion), Nov. 5, 1951 (Box 11)
- Misc. items (Box 12)
- Various legal papers concerning Hill, 1957, n.d. (Box 12)
- Deposition, complaint, summons, and memorandum re: State Bank of Binghamton, 1931-1932 (Box 12)
- Newspaper clippings, 1899, 1916-1964 (Box 12)
- Young Republican Club and RMC material, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Inauguration invitations: Hoover, Eisenhower, Truman, 1929, 1949, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Portraits of people given to Hill as gifts, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Portraits of people given to Hill as gifts, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Group photos and photos of events (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Hill with Cubs baseball team and unidentified baseball group photo (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous Photographs (Box 13)
- Large white button, “Who else but Nelse”, n.d.; MU-340 (Box 13)
- “Pen used by Governor Charles S. Whitman to sign the Hill McCue Child Welfare Bill and presented by him to Senator William H. Hill”, 1933; MU-341 (Box 13)
- Small button, “Hill for Senator”, n.d.; MU-342 (Box 13)
- Ribbon, "William H. Hill, Foreman Independent Hose Co. #1, Lestershire, N.Y.", MU-343 (Box 13)
- Portraits of William Hill, including one of him promoting the girl scouts, n.d. (Folder 1)
- Photo composite of NYS Legislature, 1915-1916 (Folder 2)
- Certificates pertaining to Central NYS Parks Commission, International Business Machines Corps. and others, 1925-1952 (Folder 3)
- Panoramic photo of dinner in honor of Pres. James A. Perkins at Waldorf Astoria, 1964 (Folder 4)
- Unidentified group of men with brooms, n.d. (Folder 4)
- Unidentified man with fish, n.d. (Folder 4)
- NY Young Republican Club dinner in honor of Hon. William H. Hill, 1918 (Folder 4)
- Complimentary Dinner, H. Murray Jacoby, 1928 (Folder 4)
- Portrait of Eisenhower, printed on satin fabric, n.d. (Folder 5)
- Photos of and with Herbert Hoover (Folder 6)
- Political cartoons by Satterfield and others (Folder 7)
- Misc. (Folder 8)
  -Including deed giving Hill ownership of Lestershire Record from Z. A. Stegmuller (1899), misc. photos, birthday cards, “Broome Likes Dick” poster, “Billy” Hill - written by Floyd Gibbons
- RNC panoramic photo, 1912 (Folder 9)
- Portrait of William McKinley, n.d. (Folder 10)
- Large engraving of Abraham Lincoln, n.d. (Folder 11)
- Plans, 1917, 1928 (Folder 12)
  -Including Lily Lakes area (1928), Johnson City Heights (1917), and Endicott area flood protection project, unit 1 – Westover (n.d.)
- Payroll records of Binghamton Republican, 1915-1924 (Volume 2)
- General accounts, probably of Johnson City Publishing Co., 1919-1924 (Volume 3)
- 1 Scrapbook newspaper clippings
- Lestershire Record (incomplete), Jan.-Dec. 1901
- Record of Johnson City, Endicott and Union, Jan.-June 1920
- Phonograph, "Jerry Beacher Visits the Hill Family", Jan. 10, 1937 (Box 14)
- Phonograph, "Lincoln Day Tributes to William H. Hill", Feb. 1960 (Box 14)